Guide to the William M. Nichols Papers 1914-1966
Montana Historical Society Archives
William M. Nichols Papers
1914-1966
Montana Historical Society Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-4774 mhslibrary@mt.gov
MC 292
Nichols, William M. (William Morse), 1881-1957.
10 linear feet of shelf space
William M. Nichols was president of the Yellowstone Park Company, the H.C. Child Corporation, the Spanish Creek Ranch, and other enterprises. Papers include general correspondence (1946-1957); financial records; minutes of the Yellowstone Park Company (1955-1962); and an extensive subject file (1914-1966) maintained both by Nichols and by his son John Q. Nichols, concerning the various corporate and financial affairs of the Nichols and Child families.
William Morse Nichols was born December 1, 1881, in Hartford, Connecticut, the son of William Ford Nichols (1849-1927) and Clara Quintard Nichols (b. 1857). He had three siblings: John W. Nichols, who became Bishop of Shanghai; Clara Nichols Mills; and Margaret Nichols Clark. While Billie--as he was always known by family and friends--was a young child, the family moved to San Francisco, where William Ford Nichols was appointed Episcopal Bishop of California. William briefly attended Trinity College in Hartford, Connecticut, from 1897 to 1899. He then was appointed to the U.S. Military Academy at West Point. He graduated in 1903 and became a second lieutenant in the 11th Cavalry, assigned to Yellowstone National Park. He resigned in 1905 to work for the Engineering Division of the Northern Pacific Railway. In 1907 he left the employ of the railroad to work as secretary to Harry W. Child, president of the Yellowstone Park Transportation Company. That same year he married Child's daughter, Ellen Dean Child. Nichols gradually moved up in the company administration, becoming assistant to the president in 1915. During World War I Nichols served as a major in supply and ordnance roles in the U.S. Army. He did not serve overseas. In 1927 he took over active management of the company from his ailing father-in-law. On Child's death in 1931, Nichols succeeded him as president. Under his presidency the various concessions in Yellowstone National Park--including the Yellowstone Park Transportation Company, the Yellowstone Park Hotel Company, and others--were merged to form the Yellowstone Park Company. William Nichols continued active management of the company until the mid 1940s when his older son, John Q. Nichols, gradually began to take over active management. In December 1956, William Nichols resigned as president of the company to take the position of chairman of the board of directors. John Q. succeeded him as president. In addition to his Yellowstone Park Company holdings, Nichols was active in the H.C. Child Corporation, the H.C. Child Trust, the Spanish Creek Ranch [Flying D Ranges, Inc.] the Green Meadow Farm, and numerous real estate ventures in Gardiner, Montana, and La Jolla, California. William M. Nichols and his wife E.D.C. "Dean" Nichols had three children: Adelaide, John Q., and Dean. Nichols died August 6, 1957, in Yellowstone National Park. Ellen Dean Child was born in 1885, the daughter of Harry W. Child and Adelaide Dean Child. Her aunt was Maria Dean, pioneer woman doctor of Helena. Her brother Huntley Child and nephew Huntley Child, Jr., were active in the management of the Yellowstone Park Company. She married William M. Nichols in November 1907. Maintaining households in Yellowstone in the summer, La Jolla, California, in the winter and Helena, Montana, in the spring and fall, Dean became active in social and charitable activities in all three towns. She donated the Adelaide Child Laboratory to St. Peter's Hospital, Camp Child to the YMCA, and money to the City of Helena for the building of Beattie Memorial Park. In addition she was instrumental in the formation of the Green Meadow Country Club. She was active, with her husband, in the management of the H.W. Child Corporation and H.W. Child Trust, and served briefly as president of the Yellowstone Park Company after the death of her husband in 1957. E.D.C. Nichols died in October 1966. Adelaide Nichols, daughter of William M. and Ellen Dean Child Nichols, was born in 1909. In 1930 she married Michael Casserly. They had two children Joan and Mariana. Adelaide later married Herrick Low, who was very active in the management of the Nichols' investments. She died in Burlingame, California, January 9, 1998. John Quintard Nichols was born in 1910. He attended Harvard University and Kelsey-Jenney business college. After graduating he worked briefly for the Wood, Struthers and Company investment firm before joining his father's company. He rose from dishwasher to transportation agent to auditing office clerk from 1935 to 1937 and then became Secretary-Treasurer in 1938. During World War II he was a captain in the U.S. Army Air Force and served in Leyte and the Philippines. In 1946 he returned to the Yellowstone Park Company. He became president in 1956, and then succeeded his mother after her brief term as president following the death of William M. Nichols. John Q. Nichols died in February 1980 in La Jolla, California. Dean Nichols was born in 1914. He trained at the Yale University School of Medicine, receiving his M.D. in 1942. He interned at Baltimore City Hospital and received further training at the Mayo Clinic. During the late 1940s and early 1950s he practiced as a dermatologist and radiologist in Helena. He also practiced medicine in Texas, California, and Arizona. He died in Phoenix, Arizona, on January 25, 1973. Harry Wilbour Child was born in San Francisco in 1857. He attended prep school in Massachusetts to prepare for Harvard, but went to work in a wholesale clothing house in Boston instead. He returned to San Francisco, where he worked as a broker with his father. He did not like the business and left California for Montana. During the early 1880s he managed mines at Gloster and Gregory for A.J. Seligman, and in 1888 moved to Great Falls to manage a silver smelter. After it closed in 1890, he moved to Helena. He took over operation of the Yellowstone Park Transportation Company on the death of his brother-in-law Silas S. Huntley in 1901. That same year the company acquired the Mammoth Hotel from the Northern Pacific Railway. H.W. Child built the hotels at Upper Basin, Grand Canyon, Fountain, Yellowstone Lake, and Mammoth. The Yellowstone Park Transportation Company owned 800 horses and 500 coaches. These horses were raised by Child in partnership with Charles Anceny at the Flying D Ranch. Child married Adelaide Dean. They had one daughter Ellen Dean Child and one son Huntley Child. Harry W. Child died February 4, 1931, in La Jolla, California.
Content Description:
Collection consists primarily of general correspondence files (1946-1957) of William M. Nichols; and subject files (1914-1966) that were maintained over the years by Harry W. Child, William M. Nichols, and John Q. Nichols. The correspondence files consist of personal letters between Nichols and a wide circle of family and friends, many of whom were also business associates. While the emphasis of the files is personal, they contain many letters concerning the operation of the various companies and concerning Yellowstone National Park management issues. The subject files contain correspondence, financial records, legal documents, and other materials organized into broad topical categories. In addition there are financial records (1914-1957) consisting principally of audit reports for several of the companies; and tax records. There are a few legal documents, and miscellaneous other records.
Arrangement:
by series
Acquisition Information:
available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Hotels--Montana; Investments; Parks--Montana; Ranches--Montana; Real estate business; Stamp collecting; Bricker Amendment; Postage stamps as an investment; Land companies; Child-Anceney Ranch (Bozeman, Mont.); Gallatin Gateway (Mont.); Green Meadow Farm (Helena, Mont.); Helena (Mont.); Yellowstone National Park--Leased departments, concessions, etc.; Gardiner (Mont.); Camp Child (Elliston, Mont.); Burlingame (Calif.); Flying D Ranch (Mont.); La Jolla (Calif.); Spanish Creek Ranch (Mont.); Montana; Sports and Recreation; Parks and Playgrounds
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Biographical Materials
  - Biographical materials (includes obituaries of William M. Nichols, Ellen Dean Child Nichols, and Harry C. Child; genealogical charts; application forms; correspondence) (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- General Correspondence
  - Col. James M. Adamson, 1956 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Horace M. Albright (former director of National Park Service; includes description of visit by New York Governor Thomas E. Dewey), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 3-5)
  - Army and Navy Club, Washington D.C., 1955-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - A (correspondents include Frank A. Allen, American Red Cross, Anderson Motors, Walter Arnholt, G.F. Ashby), 1946-1948 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Dr. Otto Barkan, 1945-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - Sen. Frank A. Barrett, 1948-1955 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - Hilda Barringer (re management of La Jolla house), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 10-13)
  - Fern Bernard, 1948 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - Boys' Clubs of America, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Howard B. Brown, 1946-1955 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - Burlingame Country Club, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - B (correspondents include E.W. Bache, Jesse G. Baldwin, Peter Bettledorf, Anthony Bliss, Gerald Clark Brant), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 1 / 18-20)
  - Dale Carnegie, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - Adelaide Casserly and family (daughter; see also Herrick Low), 1946-1956 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - Adelaide Dean Child [Mrs. Harry W. Child] (includes estate materials), 1946, 1949 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - Huntley Child (Sr. and Jr.), 1946-1954 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - William Christie (Christie Company, clothing), 1946-1955 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Church Divinity School of the Pacific, 1946-1956 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - City Dye Works (re carpets), 1946-1948 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
  - Margaret Nichols Clark [sister], 1949-1956 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - Committee for Constitutional Government, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
  - Helen Connors, 1946, 1948 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - Contintental Oil Company (includes Willis Johnson), 1950-1956 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - J.R. Coogan (re La Jolla house landscaping), 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Albert Cotsworth (Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - N.J. "Jack" Croney, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Edward Cunningham (J.M. Forbes and Company), 1948 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - C (correspondents include Elizabeth Carpenter, The Cody Club, Will Cooper, Eleanor Chittenden Cress), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Bill Daugherty (Yellowstone Park Company; Desert Inn, Palm Springs, California), 1947 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - Davis and Clifton (Burlingame, California, realtors), 1946-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - Arthur E. Demaray (associate director, National Park Service), 1946-1949 (Box-folder 2 / 17)
  - Desmond's (re chauffeurs' uniforms), 1949-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 18)
  - U.S. Representative Wesley D'Ewart, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 19-20)
  - Minnie Jean Dobie (U.S. Bureau of Reclamation), 1954 (Box-folder 2 / 21)
  - Don Doig (Automobile Club of Southern California), 1947-1955 (Box-folder 2 / 22)
  - Dale E. Doty (includes National Right to Work Committee), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 23)
  - Lewis W. and Peggy Douglas, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 2 / 24)
  - Newton B. Drury (National Park Service director), 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 25)
  - D (correspondents include John Henry Kelso Davis, Detroit International Bridge Company, Thomas E. Dewey, Charles D. Dickey, W.E. Diefenbach, U.S. Senator Henry C. Dworshak), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 26)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 2 / 27)
  - U.S. Senator Zales N. Ecton (includes planned display of Declaration of Independence), 1948-1950 (Box-folder 2 / 28)
  - Dr. George Eusterman (Mayo Clinic; re Dean Nichols' fellowship), 1946 (Box-folder 2 / 29)
  - E (correspondents include Sam Eagle, Eleanor M. Ecker, Roe Emery), 1948-1956 (Box-folder 2 / 30)
  - First National Bank and Trust Company, Helena (re investments, safe deposit, etc.; correspondents include L.S. Hazard, Fred Heinecke, Walter Brutsche), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 3 / 1-3)
  - Harry FitzGerald, Inc., Furnishers to Gentlemen, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Claire Flint, 1952 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - F (correspondents include Farmers Creamery, John W. Fisher, U.S. Representative Orvin B. Fjare), 1946-1955 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - Richard E. Gaines (La Jolla painting contractor), 1946-1952 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Hugh D. Galusha (accountant), 1946-1956 (Box-folder 3 / 8-10)
  - Max Goodsill (Northern Pacific Railway Company), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - Vernon Goodwin (Yellowstone Park Company; includes discussion of proposal to open park to winter use), 1946-1954 (Box-folder 3 / 12-13)
  - Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - Grand Teton Lodge and Transportation Company (Jackson Lake Lodge), 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - Ulysses S. Grant III (re original act establishing Yellowstone National Park; visit to Park), 1947-1955 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - Frank Gray, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - G (correspondents include Augustine James Gagliardo, Claude Gardner, Gateway Hiawatha Boys Club, Robert Everett Gillespie, Glacier Park Company, Edmund B. Gregory), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
  - Warren A. Hall (W.A. Hall and Company, Gardiner), 1951-1957 (Box-folder 3 / 19)
  - Bernard O. Hallin (Yellowstone Park Company; includes Pete and Thomas Hallin), 1946-1956 (Box-folder 3 / 20)
  - C.A. Hamilton (Hamilton Stores Inc.; includes material on rivalry with Yellowstone Park Company), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 3 / 21-22)
  - Trevor O. Hammond (re First National Bank and Trust Company; Independent Coal and Coke Company), 1948-1952 (Box-folder 3 / 23)
  - Jule M. Hannaford, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 3 / 24)
  - Hansen Packing Company (correspondents include Charles E. Woolfolk, D.J. Driscoll, J.V. Keyes), 1946-1954 (Box-folder 3 / 25)
  - Fred Harvey, Dagget Harvey, Byron Harvey (re Fred Harvey enterprises in several national parks; includes information on Don Tresidder), 1948-1955 (Box-folder 3 / 26)
  - Jack Ellis Haynes, Isabel Haynes (re photography business), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Howard H. Hays (Glacier Park Transport Company), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 2-3)
  - Fred Heinecke (see also First National Bank and Trust Company, Helena), 1949-1956 (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - Helena Community Chest, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - A.T. Hibbard (Union Bank and Trust Company, Helena), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Wetmore Hodges (Hodges Research and Development Company; re proposal for containerization of shipping and other inventions; also includes William B. Nichols), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 7-9)
  - Hotels (re Nichols family travel arrangements), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 10-12)
  - Colonel Marion W. Howze (re arrangements for Joan Casserly's attendance at West Point dance), 1950 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - H (correspondents include Ansel F. Hall, Fred Haller, Nancy Clark Hammond, Foster Hannaford, U.S. Representative William Henry Harrison, Robert M. Henry, Hillside Improvement Company [La Jolla], DeWitt V. Hutchings), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 14)
  - Lord Inverchapel (re visit to Park), 1946 (Box-folder 4 / 15)
  - George H. Johnston, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
  - J (correspondents include Maude Jackson, W.L.D. Jackson, Georg Jensen Inc., Joe Joffe, Edna Crawford Johnson, Fred T. Johnston [Lassen National Park], Jordanian embassy), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
  - Dr. Edmund L. Keeney, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - Marianne Casserly Kennan [grand-daughter], 1954-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 19)
  - Karl Kenyon (Security Trust and Savings Bank, La Jolla), 1946-1956 (Box-folder 4 / 20)
  - Kern County Land Company (John T. Pigott), 1947-1951 (Box-folder 4 / 21)
  - Dr. Otto Klein, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 22)
  - Michael Kley (re poem "The Grand Old Gal of Yellowstone"), 1954 (Box-folder 4 / 23)
  - K (correspondents include Daisy Killman, T.S. King, Dr. Melvin H. Knoeff, Robert Koppe), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 4 / 24)
  - La Jolla Beach and Tennis Club, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - La Jolla Country Club, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
  - Philip M. and Helen Lansdale, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
  - Letters of introduction, 1947 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
  - William Loeb (Manchester [N.H.] Union Leader; Associated Newspapers, Inc.), 1953-1954 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
  - Herrick and Adelaide Low (see also Adelaide Casserly), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
  - L (correspondents include various La Jolla businesses, I.H. Larom, Ludwig Liebwein, Life magazine, Livingston Community Hospital Association), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
  - General Douglas MacArthur (re Remington safe and visit to Park by son), 1948-1954 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
  - R.J. MacDonald house, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
  - Machin Shirt Company, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
  - Madame Butterfly (clothing store), 1949-1955 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
  - McDermott Fruit Company, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 5 / 12)
  - T.B. Miller Company (insurance; correspondents include T.B. Miller, George Miller), 1947-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
  - Charles F. and Clare Mills [Clare was W.M. Nichols' sister], 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 14)
  - Wayne Moffitt, 1957 (Box-folder 5 / 15)
  - Montana Automobile Association, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 5 / 16)
  - Montana Club, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 17)
  - Charles C. Moore (C.M. Ranch), 1949 (Box-folder 5 / 18)
  - Ed Moorman, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 5 / 19)
  - M (correspondents include Melvin E. Magnuson, Marshall Field and Company, Douglas McLellan and Associates, A.T. Mercier, Merck and Company, Rudolph Mikolich, Mission Garage, Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 20-22)
  - National Geographic Society, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 5 / 23)
  - Emil E. Nelson (Northern Pacific Railway; includes notice of death of Jule Hannaford), 1948-1952 (Box-folder 5 / 24)
  - Major L.B. Nelson (includes article "U.S. Army Hotelmen in Paris"), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 5 / 25)
  - Clara Quintard Nichols [mother], 1926 (Box-folder 5 / 26)
  - Dr. Dean Nichols [son], 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 27-28)
  - John Q. Nichols [son] and John Q. Nichols Jr., 1946-1955 (Box-folder 5 / 29)
  - William Ford Nichols [nephew], 1952 (Box-folder 5 / 30)
  - Nichols family, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 5 / 31)
  - Northern Pacific Railway Company (includes Emil E. Nelson), 1947-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 32)
  - N (correspondents include National Council of the Churches of Christ re ministry in Park, National Parks Association, J.C. Newsome and Company, Norwegian embassy), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 5 / 33)
  - Hilmer Oehlmann (Yosemite Park and Curry Company), 1946-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
  - O (correspondents include Captain H.D. Oberdorfer, U.S. Senator Joseph C. O'Mahoney, Out-of-Town Shop, Oxford University Press), 1946-1951 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
  - Harry Pence, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
  - Frank H. Phipps, 1948 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
  - Glenn Phipps, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
  - Atherton and Joan Phleger [grand-daughter], 1954-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
  - Ralph Pierson, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 7)
  - Hal and Betty Pomeroy [neice], 1946-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
  - H.A. Poole (re Quintard family genealogy), 1947, 1957 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
  - Allen M. Pope, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - Trev and Ellie Povah (Hamilton Stores Inc.; Ellie was Nichols' niece), 1948-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 11)
  - P (correspondents include Pacific Camera Store, Pacific Coast Record, Richard Payment, Kathryn K. Power, Mary Power, Thomas C. Power), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
  - Julianna Quest (re CARE), 1949 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
  - Alice M. Quintard Estate [aunt], 1946 (Box-folder 6 / 14)
  - Q (correspondents include Gene Quaw, Quintard Hospital), 1947, 1951 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
  - Railroads (re travel plans, lost luggage, etc.), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 16)
  - Readers digest (re subscription problems due to multiple households), 1947-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 17)
  - Allen B. Ripley, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 6 / 18)
  - Dorsey R. Rodney, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 6 / 19)
  - Edmund B. Rogers (Yellowstone National Park superintendent), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 20)
  - Helen Russell Rogers, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 6 / 21)
  - Erling Rohde Plumbing Company (re La Jolla residence), 1946-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 22)
  - R (correspondents include Meyer Rankin, John D. Rockefeller Jr., Winthrop Rockefeller, Victor Rossetti, Esther Roth), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 23)
  - St. Peter's Hospital; St. Peter's Parish, Helena, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 6 / 24)
  - Richard H. Sanger, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 6 / 25)
  - San Diego Union and Tribune, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 26)
  - Frank J. Schermann, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 27)
  - Major General Julian Schley (see also U.S. Military Academy, West Point, reunion), 1949-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 28)
  - Security Trust and Savings Bank, La Jolla (Karl Kenyon, Millard W. Smith), 1947-1956 (Box-folder 6 / 29)
  - Fred Sheriff (Sieben Ranch Company), 1946-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 30)
  - Dr. James W. Sherrill (Scripps Metabolic Clinic), 1947-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 31)
  - Sonotone Corporation (re hearing aids), 1949-1954 (Box-folder 6 / 32)
  - Squires Shirt Company, 1949 (Box-folder 6 / 33)
  - Frank Stone, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 6 / 34)
  - S (correspondents include Ah Sam, City of San Diego, U.S. Representative John P. Saylor, Dr. F.R. Schemm, Charles Scribner's Sons, Shodair Hospital for Crippled Children, J. Henry Smith, S.H. "Beau" Smith, Southern Pacific Company), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 6 / 35-36)
  - Oliver G. Taylor (National Park Service supervisor of concessions), 1947-1950 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
  - Marie McRae Temple, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
  - C.P. Tomlinson, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
  - Thomas Topping Company (re insurance; Lucille Topping), 1947-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
  - Donald B. Tresidder (Stanford University), 1946 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
  - Trinity College, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
  - T (correspondents include Charles P. Taft, Tanner Motor Tours, Time Magazine, Hillory Alfred Tolson, Treman King and Company, C. Russell Turner Jr., Tweeds and Weeds, Eldon J. Tyson), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
  - U.S. Military Academy, West Point, reunion (Julian Schley, John S. Upham, et al.), 1947-1948 (Box-folder 7 / 8)
  - U.S. Military Academy, West Point, Alumni Federation; Association of Graduates of U.S.M.A. (also includes Interim Committee of West Point Graduates reports on violations of honor code), 1949-1956 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
  - U.S. Naval Training Center, Commissioned Officers Mess, 1950 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
  - University Club, New York, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
  - Colonel John S. Upham, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
  - U (correspondents include U.S. News and World Report, United Air Lines, United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company, U.S. Adjutant General, U.S. National Park Service), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
  - C. Van Tassel, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
  - Charles Vandenhook, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 7 / 15)
  - V (correspondents include Nina Valliant, Venture Petroleum Corporation), 1946-1953 (Box-folder 7 / 16)
  - James A. Wales, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
  - Wall Street Journal (re subscription problems due to multiple households), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 7 / 18)